<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billNumber>162</billNumber>
    <createDate>2017-01-18T05:05:00Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2021-07-10T20:02:37Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <introducedDate>2017-01-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <recordedVotes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2017-01-17T20:55:46Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestTitle>Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2017</latestTitle>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>1537</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-03-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-17</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rubio, Marco [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Marco</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Rubio</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2084</lisID>
          <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8242</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <notes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>District of Columbia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Retail and wholesale trades</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2017-01-17</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-04-06T22:30:40Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill declares that a Washington, DC statute that prohibits the killing of wild birds and wild animals in DC does not authorize the DC Council, Mayor, or any DC governmental or regulatory authority to prohibit or unduly burden the ability of persons otherwise not prohibited from possessing firearms under federal law from acquiring or using for lawful purposes any firearm neither prohibited by federal law nor subject to the National Firearms Act. DC is denied authority to enact laws or regulations that discourage or eliminate the private ownership or use of firearms for legitimate purposes. </p> <p>The bill: (1) amends the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975 (FCRA) to repeal DC's registration requirement for possession of firearms, and (2) maintains the current ban on the possession and control of a sawed-off shotgun, machine gun, or short-barreled rifle.</p> <p> This bill prohibits dealing, importing, or manufacturing firearms without complying with federal law requirements.</p> <p>In the case of a sale or transfer of a handgun to a DC resident, a federally licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer of firearms in Maryland or Virginia shall be treated as a dealer licensed in DC if certain requirements are met.</p> <p>The bill prohibits selling, transferring or otherwise disposing of any firearm or ammunition to any person if the sellers or transferors know that such person is prohibited by federal law from possessing or receiving it.</p> <p>Individuals prohibited from possessing a firearm by federal law are barred from possessing a firearm in DC.</p> <p>The bill repeals specified DC policies and requirements regarding the keeping or storing of firearms and eliminates criminal penalties for possession of unregistered firearms.</p> <p>The bill amends the District of Columbia Code to: (1) allow DC property owners to prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms on their property, (2) authorize certain individuals to carry firearms in certain places and for certain purposes, (3) prescribe requirements for lawful transportation of firearms, and (4) prohibit the use of toy and antique pistols to commit a violent or dangerous crime.</p> <p>DC is authorized to prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms, except to certain lessees, within any building or structure under its control that has implemented security measures to identify and exclude unauthorized or hazardous persons or articles.</p> <p>The DC Chief of Police shall issue a five-year license to carry a concealed pistol to any qualified individual who completes the application process.</p> <p>The bill: (1) repeals FCRA requirements that a gun offender register and verify certain identifiable information with the Chief; and (2) repeals specified DC statutes in order to conform with this bill and restores any provision of law amended or repealed by such statutes as if they had not been enacted into law.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2017-01-17T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to restore Second Amendment rights in the District of Columbia.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments />
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-01-17T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s162is/xml/BILLS-115s162is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-01-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

