<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billNumber>1053</billNumber>
    <createDate>2017-02-15T05:12:52Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2020-09-28T22:06:48Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <introducedDate>2017-02-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 163, Number 26 (Tuesday, February 14, 2017)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. NADLER:H.R. 1053.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:clauses 9 and 18 of section 8 of article I and section 1 ofarticle III of the Constitution.[Page H1185]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <recordedVotes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <systemCode>hsju10</systemCode>
              <name>Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties Subcommittee</name>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2017-03-02T18:59:15Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2017-02-14T15:04:15Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports />
    <relatedBills />
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju10</systemCode>
            <name>Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-02-14</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-02-14</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-02-14</actionDate>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees />
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000002</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Nadler, Jerrold [D-NY-10]</fullName>
        <firstName>JERROLD</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>NADLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>850</lisID>
          <bioguideId>N000002</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8069</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>10</district>
        <byRequestType />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors />
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <laws />
    <notes />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Law</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Freedom of information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Health information and medical records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Right of privacy</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Law</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2017-02-14</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-03-13T18:50:04Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sunshine in Litigation Act of</b> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal judicial code to prohibit a court, in any civil action in which the pleadings state facts relevant to the protection of public health or safety, from entering an order restricting the disclosure of information obtained through discovery, approving a settlement agreement that would restrict such disclosure, or restricting access to court records, unless the court first makes independent findings: (1) that the order would not restrict the disclosure of information relevant to the protection of public health or safety; or (2) that the public interest in the disclosure of past, present, or potential health or safety hazards is outweighed by a specific and substantial interest in maintaining the confidentiality of the information and that the requested protective order is no broader than necessary to protect the confidentiality interest asserted.</p> <p>Courts are prohibited from enforcing any provision of: (1) an agreement between or among parties to the civil action, or an order entered under this bill, that restricts a party from disclosing information to any federal or state agency with authority to enforce laws regulating an activity relating to such information; or (2) a settlement agreement between or among parties to such civil action that prohibits a party from disclosing that a settlement was reached or the terms of the settlement (excluding any money paid) that involve matters relevant to the protection of public health or safety, or from discussing matters relevant to the protection of public health or safety involved in such civil action. The bill exempts from this enforcement prohibition (thus allows enforcement of) a settlement agreement provision about which the court finds that the public interest in the disclosure of past, present, or potential public health or safety hazards is outweighed by a specific and substantial interest in maintaining the confidentiality of the information in question, and the requested protective order is no broader than necessary to protect the confidentiality interest asserted.</p> <p>The bill creates a rebuttable presumption that the interest in protecting personally identifiable information of an individual outweighs the public interest in disclosure.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill shall be construed to permit, require, or authorize the disclosure of classified information, as defined under the Classified Information Procedures Act.</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2017-02-14T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>Sunshine in Litigation Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Sunshine in Litigation Act of 2017</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Sunshine in Litigation Act of 2017</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>To amend chapter 111 of title 28, United States Code, relating to protective orders, sealing of cases, disclosures of discovery information in civil actions, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Sunshine in Litigation Act of 2017</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments />
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2017-02-14T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115hr1053ih/xml/BILLS-115hr1053ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-03-02</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
      <links />
    </latestAction>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <version>1.0.0</version>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

